const DogQuiz = [
  {
    questionText: "Who is a great recourses for learning about dog behavior?",
    options: [
      "Upstate Canine Academy",
      "Pat Miller",
      "Jean Donaldson",
      "Update Canine Academy, Pat Miller, and Jean Donaldson",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Upstate Canine Academy, Pat Miller, and Jean Donaldson",
  },
  {
    questionText: "Why should you create train your dog?",
    options: [
      "It gives your dog a safe and quiet place to escape to when they feel overwhelmed or tired. Helps you know your dog is safe when you are not home. Help your travels safely with the dog. Helps with bowel control.",
      "So that they have a place to go when they are being punished",
      "You should not crate train a dog",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "It gives your dog a safe and quiet place to escape to when they feel overwhelmed or tired. Helps you know your dog is safe when you are not home. Help your travels safely with the dog. Helps with bowel control.",
  },
  {
    questionText:
      "What is WaggyTail Rescues reccomendation for introducing new pups to resident pups?",
    options: [
      "Dogs must meet outside on neutral ground",
      "You do not have to worry about introducing dogs to eachother",
      "Introduce them between a baby gate and base next steps on their reaction. If they are not getting along, keep the baby gate in place. If they are getting along, then allow them free range.",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Dogs must meet outside on neutral ground",
  },
  {
    questionText: "How long does doggy potty training take?",
    options: [
      "Between 4 to 6 weeks",
      "Between 4 to 6 months",
      "Between 3 to 4 weeks",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Between 4 to 6 months",
  },
  {
    questionText:
      "What should you do when your dog is having behavioral issues you cannot solve?",
    options: [
      "Let the dog sort it out for themself",
      "Bring them to the local shelter and surrender",
      "Contact a behaviorist",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Contact a behaviorist",
  },
  {
    questionText: "How long can a puppy/dog hold their pee?",
    options: ["2 hours", "One hour for every month they are old", "4 hours"],
    correctAnswer: "One hour for every month they are old",
  },
  {
    questionText: "How long can a puppy/dog be left alone?",
    options: [
      "Puppies: 1-2 hours. Dogs: 8-12 hours",
      "Puppies: 4-6 hours. Dogs: 10-12 hours",
      "Puppies: 2-3 hours. Dogs: 4-6 hours (or 8-9 with enough space to safely move around)",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "Puppies: 2-3 hours. Dogs: 4-6 hours (or 8-9 with enough space to safely move around)",
  },
  {
    questionText: "What can a puppy do before the are fully vaccinated?",
    options: [
      "You can *carry* your pup outside. Invite friends and family over to meet the pup. Take them to a dog free friends house. Take a puppy class. Take them for car rides.",
      "There are no restrictions for an unvaccinated puppy",
      "You can walk your dog outside wwith other dogs, go to dog parks, and meet friends and family",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "You can **carry** your pup outside. Invite friends and family over to meet the pup. Take them to a dog free friends house. Take a puppy class. Take them for car rides.",
  },
  {
    questionText: "What should you do if your dog is barking excessively?",
    options: [
      "Tell them to be quiet",
      "Lock them in their crate",
      "Find out why they are barking. Some unknown (to humans) dog bark are because they are bored, stressed, confused, or want attention. You can play with them, give them a stimulating toy, or examine what they may feel stressed or confused",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "Find out why they are barking. Some unknown (to humans) dog bark are because they are bored, stressed, confused, or want attention. You can play with them, give them a stimulating toy, or examine what they may feel stressed or confused",
  },
  {
    questionText:
      "What should you do if your dog is chew things up that they should not be?",
    options: [
      "Make sure they have toys that they can chew on. It may take some time to find the right chew toy for them. Make sure they house is properly dog proofed. Make sure they are properly exercised",
      "Tell them to stop",
      "Remove all items they chew on",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "Make sure they have toys that they can chew on. It may take some time to find the right chew toy for them. Make sure they house is properly dog proofed. Make sure they are properly exercised",
  },
  {
    questionText: "How much exercise do dogs need per day?",
    options: ["2 hours per day", "30 minutes per day.", "15 minutes per day"],
    correctAnswer: "30 minutes per day.",
  },
  {
    questionText:
      "What should you do if your dog is jumping when you do not want it to?    ",
    options: [
      "Understand why your dog is jumping, they could be anxious or stressed. If they are excited: Train your dog to sit and stay when people enter through the door. Do not give the pup attention when they are jumping.",
      "Tell it to stop until it stops",
      "Lock the dog in it's crate until the excitment trigger is gone",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "Understand why your dog is jumping, they could be anxious or stressed. If they are excited: Train your dog to sit and stay when people enter through the door. Do not give the pup attention when they are jumping.",
  },
  {
    questionText: "What are the steps for dog proofing your home?",
    options: [
      "Install low pile carpet and non slip flooring. Have pull out shelves and drawers. Choose a bed with appropriate height for entry and exit. Install ramps for ease of movement and keep clear pathways.",
      "Hide all cords, put stoppers in all the electrical outlets, put up gates for the rooms, make sure there are screens in the windows, put latches on cabinet doors.",
      "Put medications and cleaners in cabinet that is secured, install baby gates to prevent access to restricted rooms, remove breakable items from dogs line of sight, dog bed, toys for chewing and stimulation",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "Put medications and cleaners in cabinet that is secured, install baby gates to prevent access to restricted rooms, remove breakable items from dogs line of sight, dog bed, toys for chewing and stimulation",
  },
  {
    questionText: "How often should your dog go to the vet?",
    options: [
      "Only when they are showing signs of sickness or injury.",
      "On average once per year to update vaccinations and for preventative care.",
      "Dogs do not need to go to the vet",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "On average once per year to update vaccinations and for preventative care.",
  },
  {
    questionText: "Why should you train your dog?",
    options: [
      "It will improve relationship with your dog: it will trust you more. It keeps your dog safe. It improves your dogs confidence.",
      "So that they are better behaved",
      "Not all dogs need to be trained",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "It will improve relationship with your dog: it will trust you more. It keeps your dog safe. It improves your dogs confidence.",
  },
  {
    questionText: "How often to clip your dogs nails?",
    options: ["Every 1-2 months", "Every 4-6 weeks", "Every 3-4 weeks"],
    correctAnswer: "Every 3-4 weeks ",
  },
  {
    questionText: "What foods can dogs not have?",
    options: [
      "grapes, raisins, avocados, garlic, onion, chicken bones",
      "chocolate, red meat, chicken, carrots, sweet potato",
      "There are no restrictions on what a dog can eat",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Grapes, Raisins, Avocados, garlic, onion, chicken bones",
  },
  {
    questionText: "What training should your dog have?",
    options: [
      "Not all dogs need training",
      "Stop it and quiet commands",
      "Sit, walk nicely on a leash, come, stay, no jumping on people",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "Sit, walk nicely on a leash, come, stay, no jumping on people",
  },
  {
    questionText: "Why should you research dog breeds before adopting?",
    options: [
      "Becuase you should know what kind of dog you want",
      "To make sure the type of dog you are adopting matches your lifestyle. Different dog breads have different temperaments. Some are higher energy than other. Some are harder to train than others. Certain breeds have more health issues than others. ",
      "There is no need to research dog breeds before adopting a dog",
    ],
    correctAnswer:
      "To make sure the type of dog you are adopting matches your lifestyle. Different dog breads have different temperaments. Some are higher energy than other. Some are harder to train than others. Certain breeds have more health issues than others. ",
  },
];

export default DogQuiz;
